{
    "id": "cbb823c51a5d467fbda7b167b179c98d",
    "title": "Tenses Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "By the time they found him, he .................................",
            "description": "The past perfect is used to mean that something had already happened at the time we are talking about it.",
            "answers": [
                "died",
                "had died",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "He ..................................... many years ago.",
            "description": "To simply state that something happened sometime ago we use the simple past tense.",
            "answers": [
                "died",
                "had died",
                "has died"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "By that time, everybody ........................................ asleep.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "was",
                "had been"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "She told me that something ........................................ to him.",
            "description": "A simple past tense in the direct speech changes to past perfect tense in the indirect speech.",
            "answers": [
                "happened",
                "had happened",
                "has happened"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I ............................................ about it until you mentioned it.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "didn't think",
                "hadn't thought"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "She ............................................. him at once.",
            "description": "To simply state that something happened sometime ago we use the simple past tense.",
            "answers": [
                "has recognized",
                "recognized",
                "had recognized"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I ....................................... him yesterday.",
            "description": "To simply state that something happened sometime ago we use the simple past tense.",
            "answers": [
                "saw",
                "have seen",
                "had seen"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "He ......................................... in",
            "description": "We use the simple past to talk about peopleâ€™s date or place of birth.",
            "answers": [
                "born",
                "was born",
                "had born"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I ............................................... enough time to finish the job.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "didn't get",
                "hadn't got"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "When I arrived at the party, everybody .......................................... home.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "went",
                "has gone",
                "had gone"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "I wondered who ........................................... the cat in.",
            "description": "The past perfect is common after past verbs of saying and thinking.",
            "answers": [
                "let",
                "had let",
                "has let"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I thought I .......................................... the money.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "sent",
                "have sent",
                "had sent"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        }
    ]
}